Contact

443-485-7116 (Mobile) qtpeters.career@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/quinnpeters (LinkedIn)

www.nissint.com/ (Company) github.com/qtpeters (Other)

Top Skills

Software Engineering Java Pvthon

Languages

Spanish (Limited Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

ScrumMaster

Quinn Peters

Director of Software Engineering at Aquia

Washington DC-Baltimore Area

Summary

I am foremost a Software Developer. However, I have lead integration, performed DevOps tasks and even spent enough time on test teams to truly understand and value what they bring to the table. If I had my way, I would always be doing full stack development work, starting at the data source through the enterprise layer and all the way to the user interface. I am currently acting as the subject matter expert for our overall UI strategy for my section of the enterprise at Ft. Meade. This involves developing a system that will allow several teams working on dozens of web applications to componentize and share web components and libraries to ultimately standardize and unify our user interfaces to simplify maintenance and provide continuity for our customer's user experience.

I enjoy learning and working with new technologies and concepts. I believe in being a lifelong learner, who uses knowledge to improve my work, whether it pertains to software development, my relationships or my hobbies. My life goal is to become the greatest version of myself and I will never stop working for that. I thrive on productivity and thirst for results. I love working collaboratively. There is nothing more satisfying than attacking a problem or a set of problems with a good team.

My most current skills, from most skilled to least are:

- * Software Development, Design and Engineering
- * Enterprise Java
- * Apache Products and Libraries
- * Karaf
- * Commons Libs
- * Eclipse and Eclim (I'm a giant fan of Vim)
- * Maven, Gradle... Ant even.
- * Nexus, Artifactory and Archiva.
- * Java SE version 8. I have had a great opportunity to leverage Java 8 features in production recently.
- * Web Application Development using:

- * JavaScript and Node.js: Client and Server (usually with Express)
- * HTML5 and CSS3
- * AngularJS
- * Vue.js/Vuex
- * System Administration

Experience

Aquia Inc

Director of Software Engineering

February 2022 - Present (10 months)

Remote

- * Leading work building Software Bill of Materials analysis system using purely Serverless AWS Components (Lambda, Fargate, DynamoDB, Cognito, etc.).
- * Developing components using Python
- * Developing IoC using AWS CDK (Also, Python)
- * UI Development with React

Codescratch

Principal Software Engineer

July 2021 - February 2022 (8 months)

Remote

* Currently developing micro services in Kotlin, Groovy and Java

Nissint Technologies, LLC.
Principal Software Engineer
March 2014 - July 2021 (7 years 5 months)

Annapolis Junction, maryland

- * Development Lead on TreeSAP MFA.
- Working with Systems Engineering team to map requirements to actionable work for developers
- Heavily involved in development policy creation
- Developing scripts for automated build and deployment as well as machine provisioning on AWS
- Create Ansible scripts for automated, custom software installations
- Developed certificate distribution and management software on AWS
- Troubleshoot software in production and develop after action reports to notify management

- * Worked on project developing analytics for large data sets using MongoDB, Elasticsearch (ELK Stack) and Java. Developing user interfaces with React, Redux and React Bootstrap.
- * Recent experience in Web Component UI development with Vue.js, vuex, React and redux, Google APIs for sheets, Google Apps Admin SDK and Oauth2.
- * Lead development of Java thick client (Swing RaptorX). Assisted in defining and clarifying requirements, designing software architecture and feature implementation.
- * Assisted in the planning and implementation of APIs designed to simplify integration between back end services and user interfaces.
- * Developed web application features using Node.js.
- * Developed Dependency Injection Framework for Node.js to improve component modularity and

facilitate complex unit and integration testing.

- * Developed backend system to manage groups of web sockets for streaming data.
- * Used ActiveMQ JMS Broker to stream data to web sockets for use by web applications.
- * Designed and developed custom controls using d3's SVG package.
- * Developed web applications using AngularJS and BootstrapJS.
- * Used Google Flot to develop graphs that visualize system resource usage.
- * Used HTML5 to stream stored audio files.
- * Developed deployment scripts using the Bash shell and integrated them into larger build environment completely automated by Jenkins.
- * Developed Web Integration Tests using Selenium.

Collabraspace Senior Software Engineer February 2011 - March 2014 (3 years 2 months) Annapolis, MD

- * Automated installation tasks using Power-CLI for controlling virtual machines.
- * Developed RSS plugins for Media Wiki using PHP.
- * Automated software install for continuous integration using Hudson and Jenkins.
- * Developed utilities for various tasks using Java.
- * Co-Developed innovative documentation strategy involving Mediawiki's templating functionality and Windows Powershell to transform html into MS Word and PDF documents.
- * Developed module based software using Ozone Widget Framework.

- * Communication between widget services was facilitated using RESTful webservices specifically implemented with Apache Jersey and EXT/JS.
- * Led a small team in the design and development of OWF widgets to enable document viewing, report generation and geolocation using OpenLayers map API.
- * Developed Subversion triggers using Python to enforce policies regarding Trac tickets.
- * Developed custom Maven plugins to facilitate and streamline unit testing of Javascript using PhantomJS and Jasmine.
- * Engineered and implemented multi-tier test bench for integration testing.

 Solution includes nightly builds deployed to weblogic servers on the test bench with automated acceptance test emulation using Quick Test Professional.
- * Provides strong technical problem solving on issues raised by customers and troubleshoot network, server, and general system issues as required.
- * Provides software development and engineering support for team that is developing a system to manage and control software deployments.

Northrop Grumman Software Engineer II April 2008 - January 2011 (2 years 10 months)

- * Developed and maintained service responsible for taking C2 requests to start, update and stop multicast data streams used to visualize ambient energy in the electromagnetic spectrum. An API was developed to control the service and report any exceptions back to the implementor.
- * Developed and maintained middleware used to facilitate communication between our system, a third party audio player and another third party audio storage system. The audio storage used web services to request and process audio data, and due to the situation this system was developed in, the web services client had to be developed from scratch starting at the socket level rather than simply implementing already available solutions.
- * Developed and maintained API that communicated to and controlled a set of test equipment (GPIB) for hardware accuracy verification.
- * Implemented a set of algorithms to process and report test data to test operators.
- * Was assigned trouble tickets to fix bugs in various other components throughout the system. Other components included: Radio Control Unit API, audio system managers and runtime hardware fault reporting services.
- * Supported integration of various software components with each other and third party entities. This position also included systems level integration with custom hardware.

US Air Force

Network and Systems Administrator July 2004 - January 2011 (6 years 7 months)

Duties as a Drill Status Guardsman in the Oregon Air National Guard include:

* Developed remotely updateable digital phone book for Kingsley Field.

Updates were reviewed

by network administrators and approved before the database was actually updated.

- * Wrote minor updates to Sharepoint Applications in C#
- * Developed accountability database for the base to use during drill. Database included a

web application so that shop chiefs could enter their information remotely.

- * Installing all new hardware, systems, and software for networks.
- * Installing, configuring, maintaining network services, equipment and devices.
- * Supporting administration of servers and server clusters.
- * Managing all system back-up and restore protocol.
- * Planning and supporting network and computing infrastructure.
- * Perform troubleshooting analysis of servers, workstations and associated systems.
- * Documenting network problems and resolutions for future reference.
- * Monitoring system performance and implementing performance tuning.
- * Managing user accounts, permissions, email, anti-virus, anti-spam.
- * Overseeing software and network security.

Redding Design

Systems Administrator/Web Developer February 2002 - May 2004 (2 years 4 months)

- * Engineered network infrastructure and stood up services to provide small scale web hosting.
- * Designed, developed and hosted several websites for local businesses.
- * Engineered and administrated networks for local businesses including assembling custom hardware, installing and maintaining servers as well as client machines.

US Army

MTE supervisor/Web Developer April 1997 - April 2001 (4 years 1 month) Established digital telephone and data networks in a tactical environment.

Managed soldiers to accomplish these goals while maintaining light and sound discipline in arctic conditions.

Education

Cal Poly Humboldt

BS, Computer Science and Applied Mathematics · (2004 - 2007)

Air Force Tech School

Certificate of completion, COMPUTER SYSTEMS OPERATIONS, AFC - 3C071 · (2007 - 2007)

Shasta College

A.S., Computer Information Systems · (2001 - 2004)